# DONGYAN LIN

MSc Candidate, McGill University · Montreal, Canada dongyan.lin@mail.mcgill.ca · +1(204) 297-5788

I am a MSc candidate in computational neuroscience at McGill University. My research focuses on applying machine learning to neuroscience and investigating the roles of memory model in learning tasks. In addition to research, I have a strong passion for teaching and years of experience teaching mathematics and neurosciences.

## **EDUCATION**

SEPTEMBER 2019 – PRESENT M.Sc., McGill University

Program: Integrated Program in Neuroscience (IPN)

**cGPA**: 4.00/4.00

**SEPTEMBER 2015 – JUNE 2019** 

Hon. B.Sc. (with high distinction), University of Toronto (Innis College) **Programs**: Physiology Major, Psychology Minor, Mathematics Minor

**cGPA**: 3.87/4.00

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

**SEPTEMBER 2019 – PRESENT** 

Research M. Sc. Student, Mila - Quebec Artificial Intelligence Institute

Advisor: Dr. Blake A. Richards

**Project**: Reinforcement learning model of mouse hippocampal activities during Trial-Unique, Delayed Nonmatching-to-Location (TUNL) Task

- Trained actor-critic network with reinforcement learning algorithms on simulated TUNL task
- Analyzed in vivo calcium imaging data of mouse hippocampal CA1 activities with MATLAB

#### SEPTEMBER 2018 - APRIL 2019

Lab Manager/Research Assistant, University of Toronto, Department of Psychology

Advisor: Dr. Katherine Duncan

**Project**: Measuring familiarity of native English speakers to different objects with object-naming experiment

- Recruited participants and collected results with Amazon Mechanical Turk

# JUNE 2018 – AUGUST 2018

Bioinformatics Intern, RIKEN, Yokohama, Japan

Advisor: Dr. Michiel de Hoon

**Project**: Elucidating the functional roles of anti-sense transcripts in human THP-1 leukemia cells with computational methods

- Analyzed genomic data with Python and Python packages such as Bedtools
- Presented results at the Summer Undergraduate Research Symposium held by the Department of Cell & System Biology at University of Toronto and received the Best Poster Award

#### **MAY 2017 - AUGUST 2017**

Research Student, Hospital for Sick Children, Toronto, Canada

Advisor: Dr. Steve Prescott

**Project**: Investigating the chloride regulation of mouse hippocampal gamma oscillation in vitro and its potential application in pediatric medicine

- Prepared brain slices with a vibratome, and collected extracellular recordings of hippocampal neural activities using Spike2 software
- Analyzed data with MATLAB
- Presented results at University Research Opportunity Program (UROP) awardee seminar

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## **NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT**

Volunteer Classroom Instructor, BrainReach, Montreal, Canada

 Delivered 6 introductory neuroscience classes to Grade 9 students of a secondary school in Montreal.

#### SEPTEMBER 2018 – APRIL 2019

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant, University of Toronto, Department of Mathematics

- Courses: MAT135 (Calculus I), MAT136 (Calculus II)
- Prepared and delivered tutorials of 20-30 students; held office hours; graded assignment, tests, and exams; gave a guest lecture to a class of 285 students.

#### SEPTEMBER 2016 - APRIL 2018

Classroom Instructor, Easy Group Inc., Toronto, Canada

 Delivered weekly tutorial sessions to classes of 20-30 students, and exam review sessions to classes of 100-200 students on Calculus and Multivariable Calculus.

# **AWARDS**

Year	Honours / Awards	<b>Total Amount</b>
2020	IVADO Excellence Scholarship MSc	\$ 40000
2019	Recruitment Award, McGill University	\$ 5000
2018	Innis College Exceptional Achievement Award, University of Toronto	\$ 735
2018	Dean's List, University of Toronto	-
2017	University Research Opportunity Program (UROP) Award, University of Toronto	\$ 2000
2017	Innis College Later Life Learning OSOTF Award, University of Toronto	\$ 1336
2017	Dean's List, University of Toronto	-
2016	Innis College Later Life Learning OSOTF Award, University of Toronto	\$ 1289
2016	Beatty Scholarship, University of Toronto	\$ 1500
2016	Dean's List, University of Toronto	-
2015	University of Toronto Scholar	\$ 6000
2015	Canada Governor General's Academic Bronze Medal	-

# **SKILLS**

**Experimental neuroscience**: extracellular recording, animal handling, preparing brain slices

Computer programming: Python, shell scripting, Pytorch, MATLAB, LaTeX, HTML

Languages: Mandarin (native), English (fluent), French (limited)

# **VOLUNTEER & COMMUNITY SERVICE**

#### NOV 2019 - PRESENT

Organizer, UNIQUE Student Symposium, Montreal, Canada

- Plan and administer the logistics of UNIQUE (Unifying Neuroscience and Artificial Intelligence – Quebec) Student Symposium, which will be held in May 2020.

#### **MAY 2018 - APRIL 2019**

Peer Mentor, First-year Learning Community, University of Toronto

- Held bi-weekly seminars to help first-year life science students develop a sense of community, learn about university resources and become academically prepared for future studies

## **MAY 2018 - APRIL 2019**

Event Leader, iConnect Mentorship Program, University of Toronto

- Planned and organized two on-campus social events for members of the iConnect mentorship program, each with more than 50 participants
- Held monthly small group meetings to receive feedback from and provide future directions to the mentors

#### **MAY 2017 - APRIL 2018**

Mentor, iConnect Mentorship Program, University of Toronto

 Supported newly-arrived international students during their cultural transitions through online communications and city outings

# **GRADUATE COURSEWORK**

Term	Course	Grade
Winter 2020	COMP767: Reinforcement Learning	Α
Winter 2020	NEUR631: Principles of Neuroscience II	Α
Fall 2019	NEUR630: Principles of Neuroscience I	Α